Association for Research and Enlightenment Collection
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
- Publications, 1931 2015
  - Bible Studies
    - Box 51
      - minutes [Tuesday Night Bible Class], 1941-08-12 1943-05-31; Folder 51:7
    - Box 52
      - minutes [Tuesday Night Bible Class], 1945-02-06 1946-01-29; Folder 52:1
      - minutes [Tuesday Night Bible Class], 1945-03-27 1945-07-24; Folder 52:2; Denney, Ruth
      - pamphlets, 1941 1969; Folder 52:3
      - A Commentary on the Book of Revelation, 1960 1967; Folder 52:4-52:5
      - A.R.E. Bible Committee records, 1963 1965; Folder 52:6
      - A.R.E. publications on biblical study, 1941 1963; Folder 52:7
      - correspondence [Book of Revelation], 1953 1968; Folder 52:8; Turner, Albert E.
    - Box 53
      - drafts [The Book of Revelation], Folder 53:1; Turner, Albert E.
      - Extracts from the Edgar Cayce Readings on Books of the Bible: Acts through Hebrews, 1968; Folder 53:2; Turner, Albert E.
      - Extracts from the Edgar Cayce Readings on Books of the Bible: Genesis, Folder 53:3; Turner, Albert E.
      - Extracts from the Edgar Cayce Readings on Books of the Bible: Hosea through Kings, 1968; Folder 53:4; Turner, Albert E.
      - Extracts from the Edgar Cayce Readings on Books of the Bible: Leviticus through Matthew, 1968; Folder 53:5; Turner, Albert E.
      - Extracts from the Edgar Cayce Readings on the Bible, Folder 53:6; Turner, Albert E.
      - Extracts from the Edgar Cayce Readings: The Epistle of James, 1962; Folder 53:7; Turner, Albert E.
    - Box 54
      - Extracts from the Edgar Cayce Readings on the Sermon on the Mount, 1968; Folder 54:1; Turner, Albert E.
      - Extracts, Psychic Phenomena in the Bible, 1960 1968; Folder 54:2; Turner, Albert E.
      - guest book [Albert Turner's Revelation Class], 1962 1968; Folder 54:3; Turner, Albert E.
      - manuscript [Jesus' Promises in the Bible], 1964; Folder 54:4; Turner, Albert E.
      - manuscript [The Book of Revelation rewritten from the original Greek text], Folder 54:5; Turner, Albert E.
      - manuscript [The Lost Tribes of Israel], Folder 54:6; Turner, Albert E.
      - manuscript [The Revelation Decoded], 1958; Folder 54:7; Gammon, Margaret; Turner, Albert E.
      - minutes [Albert Turner's Revelation Class], 1961-09-14 1968-05-30; Folder 54:8
    - Box 55
      - notes [Bible Study Week], 1965-08-08 1965-08-14; Folder 55:1; Turner, Albert E.
      - research materials [Biblical interpretation], 1932 1968; Folder 55:2
      - research publications, 1939 1967; Folder 55:3; Turner, Albert E.
- Regions, 1931 2016
  - A.R.E. New York Center, 1931 2013
    - Box 85
      - A.R.E. activities with the United Nations, 1978; Folder 85:1
      - A.R.E. team bulletins, 1977 1981; Folder 85:2
      - by-laws [A.R.E. New York Center], 1955 1972; Folder 85:3
      - class materials, 1957 1982; Folder 85:4
      - correspondence [A.R.E. New York Center], 1951 1996; Folder 85:5-85:6
      - correspondence [A.R.E. teams], 1978 1982; Folder 85:7
    - Box 86
      - correspondence [field volunteers], 1982 1991; Folder 86:1
      - correspondence [New York State study groups], 1931 1975; Folder 86:2-86:3
      - correspondence [planning committee], 1964 1971; Folder 86:4
      - correspondence [study group policy], 1976; Folder 86:5
      - history of the A.R.E. New York Center, 1988 1989; Folder 86:6
      - index [35th Street A.R.E. books], 1968; Folder 86:7
      - indexes [publications available at A.R.E. headquarters], 1946 1977; Folder 86:8
      - lecture transcript [A Whole New You] Jeffrey Furst, 1971; Folder 86:9
    - Box 87
      - list of first inquiries, 1977 1989; Folder 87:1
      - memorial materials [David E. Kahn], 1969; Folder 87:2
      - minutes [A.R.E. New York Center Executive Council], 1955 1973; Folder 87:3
      - minutes [A.R.E. New York Center managers' meetings], 1978 1989; Folder 87:4
      - minutes [Brooklyn Council], 1981 1986; Folder 87:5
      - minutes [Long Island Council], 1973 1974; Folder 87:6
      - minutes [Nassau Long Island Council], 1977 1978; Folder 87:7
      - minutes [Queens Council], 1976 1978; Folder 87:8
      - minutes [Suffolk Long Island Council], 1978; Folder 87:9
      - minutes and correspondence [Upper and Lower Manhattan Councils], 1973 1978; Folder 87:10
      - newsletter [All God's Children], 1982 1991; Folder 87:11
      - newsletter [Ancient Mysteries], 2002 2008; Folder 87:12
      - newsletter [A.R.E. New York], 1965 1974; Folder 87:13
    - Box 88
      - newsletter [The Open Door], 1972 1980; Folder 88:1
      - photographs [conference at A.R.E. New York Center], 2000 2010; Folder 88:2
      - readings extracts [attitudes and emotions], undated; Folder 88:3
      - readings extracts [prehistory], undated; Folder 88:4
      - reports [A.R.E. New York Center], 1969 1973; Folder 88:5
      - testimonials, 1969 1973; Folder 88:6
      - Woodlands [Center for the Living Force], 1973 1974; Folder 88:7
    - Box 89, A.R.E. New York Center newsclipping collection, 1900-1990.
    - Box 90
      - A Commentary on the Book of Revelation, 1969; Folder 90:1
      - A.R.E. Community newsletter, 1992 1996; Folder 90:2
      - A.R.E. Study Group newsletters, 1964 1991; Folder 90:3
      - Book of Revelation study materials, undated; Folder 90:4
      - circulating files, undated; Folder 90:5
      - Covenant course for A.R.E. members [Herbert Puryear], 1979; Folder 90:6
      - newsletter [Perspectives on Consciousness and Psi Research], 1979 1996; Folder 90:7
      - publications [A.R.E. New York Center], 1970 2013; Folder 90:8
      - radio transcripts [The Voice of Unity] Eric Butterworth, 1974; Folder 90:9
      - readings extracts [recipients from New York], 1975; Folder 90:10
      - workshop resource notebook [Holistic Therapies for Brain-Injured Children] A.R.E. Clinic, undated; Folder 90:11
  - Regional newsletters, 1987 2016
    - Box 91
      - newsletter [Amare Kwartaalschrift] Dutch research bulletin, 1990 2001; Folder 91:1-91:2
      - newsletter [A.R.E. Belgium], 1998 1999; Folder 91:3
      - newsletter [A.R.E. Heartland], 1995 2011; Folder 91:4
      - newsletter [A.R.E. Northeast Spirit], 1993 2001; Folder 91:5
      - newsletter [A.R.E. Regional Newsletter for Northern California], 1988 1989; Folder 91:6
      - newsletter [A.R.E. Southwest Sunrays], 1994 2001; Folder 91:7
      - newsletter [The Chicagoland A.R.E. Edgar Cayce Holistic Center], 2011; Folder 91:8
      - newsletter [Edgar Cayce Centre in Durham], 1988 2000; Folder 91:9-91:10
      - newsletter [Edgar Cayce Freundes-Kries], 1996 1999; Folder 91:11
      - newsletter [The Golden Gateway], 1995 2001; Folder 91:12
      - newsletter [Living in the Light] John Van Auken, 1999 2000; Folder 91:13
      - newsletter [Love Letters: Lake Erie / Ohio Valley Regional Newsletter], 1995 2001; Folder 91:14
      - newsletter [Mid-Atlantic Messenger], 1994 2001; Folder 91:15
      - newsletter [Mountain Valley Echo], 1998; Folder 91:16
      - newsletter [Nyhetsbulletinen: The Northern Edgar Cayce Society of Sweden], 1997 2001; Folder 91:17
      - newsletter [The Open Door], 1998; Folder 91:18
      - newsletter [The Open Road], 1995 2016; Folder 91:19-91:21
      - newsletter [Pacific Northwest Spirit], 1993 1996; Folder 91:22
      - newsletter [Pacific Southwest Region Newsletter], 1995 1997; Folder 91:23
      - newsletter [Rocky Mountain Hi], 1995 2003; Folder 91:24
      - newsletter [Southern Lights], 1987 2004; Folder 91:25
      - publications [A.R.E.] French, 1999 2000; Folder 91:26
- Research, 1883 2003
  - A.R.E. Clinic, 1963 1995
    - Box 92
      - Chiropractic Reference Notebook, 1973; Folder 92:1
      - covenant agreement [A.R.E., A.R.E. Clinic], 1976; Folder 92:2
      - newsclippings [A.R.E. Clinic], 1969 1987; Folder 92:3
      - newsletter [A.R.E. Clinic Bulletin], 1977 1995; Folder 92:4
      - newsletter [A.R.E. Clinic Medical Research Bulletin: Pathways to Health], 1978 1995; Folder 92:5-92:6
      - newsletter [Energy Medicine Research News], 1988 1989; Folder 92:7
      - newsletter [The Nurse-Healers' Courier: East West Academy of Healing Arts], 1976; Folder 92:8
      - pamphlet [A.R.E. Medical Clinic], 1963; Folder 92:9
      - Physician's Workbook [Scleroderma], 1978; Folder 92:10
      - Proceedings of the 6th Annual Medical Symposium: A Symposium on Varieties of Healing, 1973; Folder 92:11
      - Proceedings of the 7th Annual Medical Symposium: New Horizons in Healing, 1974; Folder 92:12
      - Proceedings of the 8th Annual Medical Symposium: The Healing Mechanism: An Adventure in Consciousness, 1975; Folder 92:13
      - Proceedings of the 9th Annual Medical Symposium: Holistic Patient Care and the Role of Body Energies, 1977; Folder 92:14
      - Proceedings: A Symposium on Mind-Body Relationships in the Disease Process, 1972; Folder 92:15
      - Program Review and Development: A.R.E. Clinic, 1976; Folder 92:16
      - registration materials [The Creative Living Program], 1982; Folder 92:17
      - registration materials [The Temple Beautiful Program], 1982; Folder 92:18
      - report [Colonic Irrigation: An Evaluation of Several Factors it its Use at A.R.E. Clinic], 1976; Folder 92:19
      - report [Disease as a Biofeedback Device for the Transformation of Man], 1973; Folder 92:20
      - report [eye case], 1975; Folder 92:21
      - report [Five Month Progress Report on a Neurological Disease Treatment Program], 1975; Folder 92:22
      - report [Hemispheric Specialization of Cognitive Function in Learning Disabled Children], 1976; Folder 92:23
      - report [Neurological Disease Treatment Program], 1976; Folder 92:24
      - report [The Study and Treatment of Minimal Brain Dysfunction], 1976; Folder 92:25
      - welcome packet [A.R.E. Clinic], 1989; Folder 92:26
  - A.R.E. Health Services, 1883 2003
    - Box 93
      - applications [A.R.E. Referral Health Care Professionals] A-C, 2001 2003; Folder 93:1
      - applications [A.R.E. Referral Health Care Professionals] D-G, 2001 2003; Folder 93:2
      - applications [A.R.E. Referral Health Care Professionals] H-L, 2001 2003; Folder 93:3
      - applications [A.R.E. Referral Health Care Professionals] M-R, 2001 2003; Folder 93:4
      - applications [A.R.E. Referral Health Care Professionals] S-Z, 2001 2003; Folder 93:5
      - patient files [A.R.E. Health and Rejuvenation Research Center] A-D, 1998 2001; Folder 93:6
      - patient files [A.R.E. Health and Rejuvenation Research Center] E-K, 1998 2001; Folder 93:7
      - patient files [A.R.E. Health and Rejuvenation Research Center] L-R, 1998 2001; Folder 93:8
      - patient files [A.R.E. Health and Rejuvenation Research Center] S-Z, 1998 2001; Folder 93:9
      - medical research files [A], 1998; Folder 93:10
      - medical research files [B], 1998; Folder 93:11
      - medical research files [C], 1998; Folder 93:12
      - medical research files [D], 1998; Folder 93:13
    - Box 94
      - medical research files [E-H], 1998; Folder 94:1
      - medical research files [I-O], 1998; Folder 94:2
      - medical research files [P-S], 1998; Folder 94:3
      - medical research files [T-Z], 1998; Folder 94:4
      - animated ash; carbon ash, 1954 1987; Folder 94:5
      - appliances, general, 1929 1985; Folder 94:6
      - A.R.E. approved suppliers, 1978; Folder 94:7
      - atomidine, 1982 1984; Folder 94:8
      - audiocassette [interview with Buddy Adelman on the wet cell appliance], 1985; Folder 94:9
      - binder [appliances], 1949; Folder 94:10
      - binder [Atlantic Research Associates], 1974; Folder 94:11
      - binder [radio-active appliance] Lorraine Galley, 1960; Folder 94:12
      - Cayce formulas [clary flower; garden sage; ginseng; lime water; sarsparilla root], 1970 1980; Folder 94:13
      - colon therapy, 1976 1987; Folder 94:14
      - correspondence [A.R.E. Health Services], 1974 1976; Folder 94:15
      - correspondence and reports [appliances], 1957 1993; Folder 94:16
      - correspondence [Irene Hotten], 1975 1980; Folder 94:17
    - Box 95
      - etheronics / radionics, 1970 1980; Folder 95:1
      - ipsab / TIM, 1976 1982; Folder 95:2
      - medications from the Edgar Cayce Readings, A.R.E. Clinic Medical Symposium, 1976; Folder 95:3
      - participation forms [Appliance Research Project], 1981; Folder 95:4
      - patents for therapeutic appliances collected by Gustave Miller, 1883 1950; Folder 95:5
      - proposal [Cayce-Reilly Health Service], 1983 1984; Folder 95:6
      - proposal [Health Home Remedies Corporation], 1983; Folder 95:7
      - publications [A.R.E. Health Services], 1944 1978; Folder 95:8
      - radio-active appliance, 1923 1980; Folder 95:9-95:10
      - radio-active appliance experiment, 1989; Folder 95:11
      - radio-active appliance material [Joseph R. Myers], 1975; Folder 95:12
      - report [A.R.E. Health and Wellness Center], 1993; Folder 95:13
      - research [Health Home Remedies products], 1980; Folder 95:14
      - research [Health Home Remedies products], 1982 1984; Folder 95:15
      - ultra-violet appliances, 1973; Folder 95:16
      - wet-cell appliance, 1971 1976; Folder 95:17-95:18
    - Box 96
      - correspondence [The Heritage Store], 1972 1984; Folder 96:1-96:4
    - Box 97
      - correspondence [The Heritage Store], 1972 1984; Folder 97:1-97:2
      - product [The Heritage Store], 1982; Folder 97:3
  - Research Advisory Committee, 1973 1987
    - Box 98
      - correspondence [A.R.E. Research Advisory Committee], 1973 1987; Folder 98:1
      - experiment [dreams] conducted by Henry Reed, 1975; Folder 98:2
      - experiment [meditation] conducted by Herbert Puryear, 1974; Folder 98:3
      - minutes [A.R.E. Research Advisory Committee], 1973 1977; Folder 98:4
      - projects, 1973 1978; Folder 98:5
      - project [common cold], 1978; Folder 98:6
      - research [ESP], 1976; Folder 98:7
      - research [hyperactive children], 1973; Folder 98:8
      - transcript [A.R.E. meditation course] Mark Thurston, 1976; Folder 98:9
- Youth Activities, 1970 2000
  - Box 99
    - application [federal surplus program], 1982; Folder 99:1
    - binder [curricula] Kitty Campbell, 1973; Folder 99:2
    - binder [Green Woods School], 1980 1983; Folder 99:3
    - binder [Youth Activities] Robert Witt, 1980 1983; Folder 99:4
    - book [For the Love of Children: A Handbook; Concepts and Tools for Guiding Children based on the Edgar Cayce Readings] A.R.E. Youth Activities Staff, 1993; Folder 99:5
    - book [The Listening Ear] Lila Selover, 1995; Folder 99:6
    - documents and notes [Carolyn DiPaolo], 1982 1983; Folder 99:7
  - Box 100
    - financial records [Green Woods School], 1981 1982; Folder 100:1
    - minutes [Green Woods School Advisory Council], 1982 1983; Folder 100:2
    - minutes [Green Woods School faculty meetings], 1982 1983; Folder 100:3
    - newsletter [All God's Children], 1982 1991; Folder 100:4
    - newsletter [A.R.E. Youth and Family Department], 2000; Folder 100:5
    - notebook [Green Woods School budget and enrollment], 1982 1983; Folder 100:6
    - notebook [readings extracts], undated; Folder 100:7
    - publication [Kundalini for Youth] master copy; Helen Ruth Schroeder, 1970 1985; Folder 100:8
    - report [A.R.E. Research School to A.R.E. Board of Trustees] Robert Witt, 1982; Folder 100:9
    - reports [Green Woods School], 1982 1983; Folder 100:10
    - script [Second Grade's Language Play, Patten School, Pittsburgh, PA] Sandy Czernicki, 1980; Folder 100:11
  - Box 101
    - slide photographs [Green Woods School], 1981 1982; Folder 101:1
    - thesis [The Guidance and Training of Children According to the Edgar Cayce Life Readings for Children] Anita H. Peterson, 1989; Folder 101:2